Michał Wadowski

Senior Java Developer

Contact

Address

Warsaw, Poland

Phone

+48 796 334 459

E-mail

wadosm@gmail.com

Github

https://aithub.com/Michal-Wadowski

Experience and knowledge

Programming languages / technologies

Java: JUnit/Mockito, Lombok, Hibernate

Spring: Boot, Security, JPA, Kafka Javasript: ES6, JSX, ReactJS, Redux

Python: DataFrame, Numpy

Databases

PostgreSQL/pgSQL, MongoDB

Other tools / technologies

Kubernetes, AWS, Azure, Docker compose, Maven, GIT, Jenkins

Good practices

TDD, DDD, Clean architecture, software

design patterns

IDE

IntelliJ IDEA

Operating systems

Linux, Windows

Software Development Model

SCRUM

Languages and technologies in past

Android in Kotlin

C, C++

I'm a software development passionate with over 14 years of experience in various technologies and languages. I have been working in Java oriented projects for 5 years mostly using Spring Boot in combination with AWS / Azure, Kubernetes, Kafka, PostgreSQL, MongoDB. I value clean code, TDD and other good programming practices.

Professional experience

HSBC Service Delivery (Polska) Sp. z o.o.

/ Mindbox S.A. 08.2022 - 12.2024 Senior Java Developer

Developing "Strategic Financial Planning" internal business application written in Java 8 - 21 with **Spring Boot** in microservices architecture.

Technologies used: JUnit & Mockito, Java Reactor,

Lombok, PostgreSQL & Oracle

Kubernetes with AWS, Jenkins and ReactJS were

used in project as well

Orange Polska S.A.

02.2022 - 07.2022

Java Developer with

Developing microservices for streaming platform

using Kafka, MongoDB and Java Reactor

Orange Polska S.A.

02.2021 - 07.2022

Java Developer

Developing Eclipse Leshan library

https://www.eclipse.org/leshan in Java for IoT communication protocol (Lightweight M2M).

Orange Polska S.A.

Java Developer

08.2020 - 07.2022

Developing research application ThingIn The City using Spring Boot and PostgreSQL technologies.

Orange Polska S.A.

Android Developer

03.2020 - 01.2021

Developing mobile application for technicians

using Live Objects platform

https://liveobjects.orange-business.com with Android Studio in Java and Kotlin languages.

As a development model was used SCRUM

framework.

Awans Sp. z o. o.

Full-stack Developer

06.2014 - 02.2020

Developing https://awanser.pl business platform

using technologies:

Frontend: ReactJS with Redux and Ecmascript 6,

CSS, LESS and SCSS

Backend: PHP and CakePHP framework. PostgreSQL database system, Azure

Courses

Creating μ Services using Spring Cloud and Docker

https://www.altkomakademia.pl

Spring Framework II

https://www.altkomakademia.pl

Pragmatic refactoring using DDD techniques

https://bottega.com.pl

Clean Code in Java

https://pragmatists.thinkific.com

Test-Driven Development in practice https://pragmatists.thinkific.com

Useful characteristics

Writing good quality code Experienced in working with legacy systems

IT technologies quick learner Teamwork skills

Independence and responsibility

Languages

Polish

Native

English

B2

Passions & hobbies

Programming microcontrollers and developing electronic circuits Building and training artificial neural networks

Developing applications and devices for own needs

Astronomy, quantum physics and science in general

Zeto Olsztyn Sp. z o. o. Java Developer

01.2013 - 05.2014 Developing integration layer with ePUAP system in

Java and PostgreSQL + PL/pgSQL

Zeto Olsztyn Sp. z o. o. Software Developer

10.2011 - 12.2012 Developing of business application in **Delphi** and

PostgreSQL + PL/pgSQL

iDelfi Polska Sp. z o. o. Full-stack Developer

11.2009 - 12.2010 Developing internet application for HACCP

management in technologies: Ruby on Rails,

Javascript, jQuery, MySQL

Training

March 2022 Professional Scrum Developer

I (PSD I)

Education

2009 - 2011 University of Warmia and Mazury in Olsztyn

Field of study: Computer science

M. Sc.

2005 - 2008 University of Warmia and Mazury in Olsztyn

Field of study: Computer systems

Undergraduate course